[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of tosca modules
and guide you to scan application to
create modules which will be required
for test automation
all right
let's starts with the tosca modules
conceptually the tosca modules keeps the
technical properties of any control that
is referred to any test object
basically module creation is the first
step to start with test case development
in tosca
modules maps a page or screen for the
application under test with the tosca
the controls or the objects which are
required for test automation has to be
captured in module as module attributes
[Music]
tosca modules are classified into two
categories classic modules which are
created by classic engines during the
scanning
and x modules which are based on the
tosca t-box framework
all right
let's starts with the tosca modules
conceptually the tosca modules keeps the
technical properties of any control that
is referred to any test object
[Music]
basically module creation is the first
step to start with test case development
in tosca
modules maps a page or screen for the
application under test with the tosca
the controls or the objects which are
required for test automation has to be
captured in module as module attributes
tosca modules are classified into two
categories based on the architecture
classic modules which are created by
classic engines during the scanning
and x modules which are based on the
tosca t-box framework
the icons of modules are similar to this
the each components of a module are
known as module attributes and the
components are known as controls
the classic modules have the classic
module attributes and on the other hand
the x modules have the x module
attributes
now let's understand the different types
of tosca engines which will help to
automate any applications
classic engines
in the early phase of tosca classic
engines are developed to process as
though the test case information and
steers the test object
there's respective engines are available
to steer any test object
t-box
the reference of toskat box framework
algorithm is the basis for x engines to
steer any controls
same can be applied to steer gui and
non-gui objects
x engines
with the help of x definitions the x
engines are defined in tosca
the controls for the test objects are
hierarchically structured through the x
definition
so the tree structure of the test
objects are mapped with controls of any
modules
[Music]
the tosca t-box is compatible with the
most of the tosca engines such as tosca
x-scan 3.0 any ui engine 3.0 tosca ap
engine 3.0 tosca database engine 3.0
tosca.net engine 3.0 tosca mobile engine
3.0 tosca sap engine 3.0 etc
please visit
s colon http
slash
lambdageeks.com tosca hyphen modules
to learn more on tosca engines
based on the usage two types of modules
are available in tosca
standard modules can be imported or
loaded during workspace creation
standard modules are defined by tosca
which are used to perform very common
operations such that open file invoke
application string operations buffer
operations verifications etc
[Music]
user defined modules are defined by the
tester during the test case automation
this modules are developed by scanning
the applications
each of the modules represents a logical
functional block
[Music]
let's see the most commonly used
standard modules
based on the usage we can group the
standard modules in three categories
those are
t-box automation tools which are used to
perform basic operations such as basic
windows buffer file folder string date
time process resource handling etc
t-box x engines modules are used to
perform the basic operations in
different applications such as database
html
net sap mobile etc
test data related modules are used to
manage the test data through the
features such as test data management
test data services
this are the frequently used standard
modules for any test automations
but apart from this tosca provides many
modules to support test automation
activities
now we will discuss about the most
important toska scan feature
scanning through tosca is an approach to
create user-defined custom modules which
contain all the technical information
for any test applications
tosca provides many engines to scan
various applications
through this tutorial we are going to
learn about
tosca scan to create classic modules
and task a scan to create t-box modules
we can initiate tosca scan either right
clicking on module folder or selecting
the dynamic menu modules and click on
scan icon
also standalone tosca scan wizard is
available to perform classic scanning
i am going to demonstrate the scanning
approach to create user-defined t-box
modules
here we are using google search engine
portal as a test application and we are
keeping it open in a web browser
we will add three objects
search box google icon and google search
button during the scanning
[Music]
i am going to work with the multi-user
workspace which was previously created
first we will clean the tosca commander
view
to do so we will close all the tabs
except the project view
now as we are working on the modules we
will dock the modules section in the tab
list by selecting the plus option after
right clicking on modules component
in the module section the standard
modules were displayed which will be
used during the test case creation phase
by default t-box automation tools t-box
x engines and test data related modules
are available
now we will create one new folder to
store the newly created modules
we can give a logical name for the newly
created module folder
the scanning can be initiated from the
modules tab which is available in tosca
commander header section or by
right-clicking on the folder option
after clicking on the scan option all
the scanning option is showing
as we will scan web application using
box approach we will select the
application option and wait for
application selection screen
it will take few seconds to appear the
select application screen
in the meantime tosca identifying and
listing all the open applications which
are active in the desktop
those applications will be shown in
select application screen
[Music]
the desire web application need to
select and click on scan button to
proceed
now the tosca starts the scanning the
google page
after this the x can screen will appear
which displayed the list of scanned
objects
here we will use the select on screen
feature to choose objects directly from
the applications
here we will click on search text box
google icon and google search button to
add this objects
the three objects are added but one is
uniquely identified and two are not
now i will explain how we can identify
them uniquely tosca follows four
different methods to recognize any test
objects or controls during
scanning the identified by properties
methods the controls are getting
identified based on the technical
properties
in identify by anchor method the
controls are getting identified with the
reference of other controls
[Music]
in identify by image method the bitmap
of the objects are used to recognize the
controls
[Music]
if all the methods fail we should use
the identify by index method which
indicated the occurrence of same types
of objects
always we should prefer to recognize
objects by identify by properties method
in our case first we will try to
identify the google logo object based on
the alt technical property
after this the control is properly
identified
now we try to identify another google
search button object to be recognized
after analyzing the properties we
observe that all suitable technical
properties are already selected
[Music]
so we have to follow other object
recognition methods
it is advisable to use the identify by
anchor method the technical properties
are failed to identify controls uniquely
we will use another stable object queue
as the reference anchor control
if there is not properly identified
controls are available we should not use
this method
with the reference of this anchor we
will try to identify the google search
button uniquely
to do so let's drag the cue control and
drop it into anchor control section
now the object is getting recognized
uniquely with the reference of another
control
it is always advisable to rename the
controls based on the logical name
it will help to understand the purpose
of the controls future
now we need to save the scan controls to
create the modules
this newly created module is available
in the custom folder under the module
section
we can view the control properties as
parameters from the modules
the property section is available in the
right side of the screen
as we are working in multi-user
workspace environment we need to click
on check in all button to save the
modules in central repository
[Music]
similarly we will create few more
modules for google search
those modules will be used in next video
tutorial to develop the test cases
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca modules and
scanning
we will learn more about tosca test
automation in next tosca tutorial
[Music]
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query